Contact

+573015487383 frandak2@gmail.com LinkedIn

Main skills

Data Science
Machine Learning
Deep learning
Learning AWS

Education Platzi

- -School of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence
- -School of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning
- -School of AWS (currently)

University of Valle (CO)

Topographic Engineering, remote sensing - GIS

Certifications

Apache Airflow Course Backend Development Course Machine Learning: Model Optimization

AWS Partner: Accreditation (Technical)

Professional Course on Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn Convolutional Neural Networks Professional Course with Python using Keras and TensorFlow Natural Language Processing Fundamentals Course with Python and NLTK

Docker Fundamentals Course FastAPI: Fundamentals, Path Operations and Validations Course Introduction to Machine Learning Model Deployment Course Spark to Big Data Fundamentals Course

Introduction to AWS: Cloud Computing Fundamentals Course Introduction to AWS: Compute, Storage and Databases Course Storage on AWS Hands-on Course

Frank Montenegro Hurtado

Data science | Python | AWS | R | Machine learning | Deep Learning | Scikit-learn| TensorFlow | Docker | SQL | Git | Remote sensing | GIS

About me

Geomatics engineer by profession and data scientist by choice with years of experience involved and passionate about the whole software development lifecycle using frameworks like Sklearn, TensorFlow and Pytorch in Python and SQL . In my current role I am implementing pipeline development for training Machine Learning and Deep Learning models and use AWS to deploy the models in the cloud created ondemand consumer APIs. Also, I love to share what I have learned, that's why I often volunteer to mentor new members .

Experience

RAPPI – Sr. Data Scientist - Agu. 2022 – Jan 2023 Responsibilities:

- Creation of retraining pipelines with data and model versioning, improving the retraining process by **80%**.
- In-depth analysis of churn vs. debt to detect unpaid debt.
- Creation of a **spatial analysis** of churn vs. unpaid debt, detecting critical areas and generating a **20**% recovery of unpaid debt.
- Creation of a dashboard to compare the impact between 2 different models in production

Technology stack: Python, Sklearn, TensorFlow pandas, Snowflake, SQL

MASIV - Semi-senior Data Scientist - Feb. 2022 – Agu. 2022 **Responsibilities:**

- ETL generation for model input.
- Improved performance of **anomaly score** prediction model by UserAgent and location by **75% and 120%** respectively.
- Creation of **MLOps** system for retraining, monitoring, and versioning for model maintenance over time on **AWS**, increasing its **reproducibility by 100%**.
- Creation of **API for on-demand** ML model consumption, improving its response by 45%.

Technology stack: Python, Sklearn, pyspark Docker, ECR, Glue, Batch, DynamoDB, S3, Lambda on AWS

CLARO - Data Scientist - Dec. 2021 – Feb. 2022 **Responsibilities:**

- Analyze spatial information for feature selection improving model performance by 15%.
- Create a prioritization model increased selection of optimal zones by 35%.
- develop neural network architecture to predict spatial-temporal market behavior

Technology stack: Python, Sklearn, TensorFlow, geopandas, Numpy, SciPy

CIAT - Data Scientist - Oct. 2018 – Oct. 2021 **Responsibilities:**

- Created a banana classification model in mixed fields using drone and satellite images with an accuracy of 93% and 85% respectively.
- Analyzed the time series to determine points of crop changes due to the implementation of irrigation systems, with an accuracy of 80%

Technology stack: Python, Sklearn, TensorFlow, geopandas, Numpy, SciPy, Docker